It's yeah like
an experience where it's helped you learn like a positive experience something that
you should just give me like a quick rundown on what you just did because I have not already
yeah
okay
we're all going out
you guys will get
the room to yourself to just chat for the entire
space. So
I
can't mute audio.
Andrew, you're still on me.
sorry about that.
You can zoom calls me. Okay,
I kind of talked about how
using it from model generation feels a little limiting because we can't directly edit those
models. you could pull them into on shape and you could add a little bit to them, but
it doesn't work very well.
Sorry, I feel like a little echo,
right?
You are, Sterling left this computer on. Oh. No worries, though.
And then I agree with these points that it doesn't feel like our skills
are being utilized very well, with this model generation, it would be way easier to just
make configurations on one cat model rather than having AI generate everything, having
to tune every little structure that are curious.
And if you're making those models, you don't get to know those models as well, which means
it is harder to fix them if they're having issues or sometimes they have geometry errors,
the mess of things that if a human had made them, you know, would have been fine, because
we wouldn't have done that right off the bat.
Yeah,
I'm really
worried about the real things where we've got a lot of AI generate a lot of what we're
writing to the point where, like, I spent a lot of time writing my abstract, and we ended
up feeding it through AI, added a bunch of sources and like me afterward and I didn't really
that was the way to go. I think that we should have read those sources.
And yeah, that's about the helpful is that it can teach you things and
I think that's
the
best use of me as a resource. And so it was really helpful for debugging
a 16 3D printer for me.
But I
feel like it I feel like we're pushing other areas.
And
I think AI has been super good as like, I've been thinking of it as like an assistant
in a lot of ways where like I use AI a con for the lab and then for like my work and stuff.
Just to like help myself stay organized,
I have found that super useful.
I've also found it super useful to, like, be able to, like, write code and stuff with it,
but when doing that, I think it's essential to, like, go back and actually understand what
the code is doing. So, like, I'll use AI and generate a ton of code,
and then I'll go back through all of it and figure out what the heck it just did and what
I want to change or what I need to optimize. Because it doesn't usually get it quite right.
It might make it function, but it won't quite work exactly like I want or need it to. So
I found that super interesting. I think the biggest thing is just recognizing that we're
going to have AI forever. Like, there's no getting away from any of that. We really need
to find a way to harness the power that it has to make us more, like, effective and
efficient.
If you don't know how to use it, you're going to fall behind. That being said, if that's
all you use, you're useless because anyone can use AI. Right.
That's kind of my thoughts. I don't know. As far as using it in the lab, I guess I don't
know. Like, I use it a lot in the lab to, like, research stuff, just because it seems to
do, it's a really quick way to, like, compare stuff that takes a lot of the grunt work out
of it.
Yeah, and it's kind of finding information really fast,
too. Like, when I ask it to compare a mass amount of 3D metal printers, like, it's really
good at going to websites and pulling data and giving me a table that displays most results.
And that saves me a ton of time, right? I don't have to go track down all that information.
Like, it's just giving to me. And it's right. You know, I mean, it's accurate. It pulled
that from their site.
When I ask AI to do other things, sometimes it'll, like, just completely hallucinate. When
I ask it for, like, how can I build this equation to optimize this process? It has no idea.
And so it'll just spit something random. And if I run with it, like, I'm an idiot for trusting
it completely and not trying to verify what it's doing. Yeah,
I agree with that, especially with finding sources. I think it's important to go and read
through those ourselves, or at least skin, you know, make sure that we're talking about the
right things.
Yeah,
and like, just from, like, my short internship work experience that I've seen, it's, it's
everywhere. Like, literally half of my day is working with AI to optimize a process.
Oh, are you in internship right now?
Yeah, I am.
Oh, Max, what are you doing?
Like, structural engineering stuff. Cool.
So, not quite mechanical, but close enough, and it's a work experience. But I found it so,
yeah, and I found it just so interesting, like, how often they use Gemmonin and Klaug
and all these things. Like, they are into it really deep. And so a lot of, like, my internship
has been, like, finding the limits of AI. for them and then saying, hey, this is as far as
we can push this.
Like, lots of their tools are using AI to verify human work. And in the process, like, they
will be able to really
cut
down in, like, the amount of man-hours and manpower that they need to do stuff because AIs
are so effective at doing what I call the grant work.
And so I think that's super interesting to see it. It's like, this isn't going anywhere.
Any business that's like wants to be strong is going to use this and then have someone verify
it.
So I think it's really interesting to see what the world will become because all of a sudden
you're, I don't know, I think it's really interesting. You just have to verify. You verify
your sources, verify the work, verify the equations.
And once you kind of do that, like, it's the math, it usually does pretty well on. Especially
where like a lot of the stuff I'm working with is kind of, of like our material, not material
science, but mechanics and materials class. And so I think this applies to the lab to it.
It does a lot of like easy grunt work very quickly and effectively. It just can't be allowed
to make like core decisions or like core tat or else it'll just belly flop.
Yeah, I agree with that.
And part of it is figuring
out that was a rant
grunt work that it can manage too, right? Like, I mean, we've spent months trying to get
it to work with the CAD models, and it's just not doing very well, and I
think
that's okay, because I think plenty of us actually enjoy doing CAD, you know?
And every CAD model is going to be different. It wouldn't be, like, recording data and sorting
it and stuff. Like, that's something that AI would be amazing for.
But, yeah,
it's a little,
yeah. That's one of the limits I think that AI has is it's not very good at generating those
structures that we need.
Generating images and like spatial awareness AI is very poor at. It does really well with
like analyzing information and like things to do with like words and things like that. It
goes very good at image analysis, spatial analysis, things like that. It's not there.
Yeah, it doesn't live in the 3D world with us. It's all just code and stuff. And it can be
super helpful for code. I mean, I've been a little more careful with generating so much
code at once because often it'll come up with, like, a function or something that I haven't
ever used before, and I'll be like, hey, what's that? And then it takes a little more time,
but then you're still learning with it, but often it can feel a little like you're trying
to catch up to where AI is at, and you're never going to get to that point. but you
learn
a lot,
but I think it's ultimately better writing my own code because then I know exactly how
it works and how I want it to be working.
That's my opinion. If you
have one of the subs.
We might,
I think we'll jump
back together to,
yeah, let's jump to the next question.
So let's just kind of shift it over to lab culture. So like in the vertical cloud
lab at BYU specifically,
what kind of things could we do? Like, what kind of conversations could we have to help out?
Like, what kind of lab culture do we want? How do we set that kind of culture here? Especially
as new people come in, as people graduate and then pass off the baton, you know, what
is the lab culture? like that
so regarding AI or just general
AI
yeah and then I think it would be good to in future what's
a breakoff talk for me.
We'll do break off yeah another break off in the side.
Yeah, yeah, and we're
going too.
Sorry,
you guys can keep going. Sorry,
you guys can keep going. What do you think, Audrey?
I
don't know, I'm bad, I use AI a lot, like a lot, a lot, a lot.
As far as like the culture of it, I think that's very personal. I know, like, Xavier doesn't
use it very much at all.
Yeah.
I mean, do you still feel like you're learning and that you're capable when you're using
it, though?
Yes and no.
Yes and no. There are times, kind of like what you're saying at the end, I literally will
chase AI through, like, tons of code trying to figure out how it's doing, what it's doing.
I mean, at the end of the day, I come back to it and kind of just, like, look at it, And
it's like, well, it's working. I have a kind of a grasp of what I think it's doing. Oh, it's
doing it. I don't know how that function exactly works. Like, I really don't know.
But it works. And I think I know kind of what it's doing. Could I, like, teach someone else
what it's doing? No. Yeah. And so I guess I trust it maybe too much in
that sense.
That being sad,
like,
for me, it's kind of, of like the means to the end on like certain things. Like I would prefer
not to be coding stuff my whole life and so that's not something that entreats me. And so
maybe I'm short circuit, like short-circuiting my education in that aspect. But at the same
time,
it's something that I don't hope to be doing my whole life.
Gotcha. So you're not worried about your coding skills. Yeah. So like, you don't see yourself
using them very much.
Like long term, yeah, I'm not as worried about that. where I do spend, like, a lot more time
understanding is things with, like, the 3D printers and, like, material science stuff. Like,
that's just information that I need to know, like, forever. And so, like,
when it comes to those things and I'm using AI, like, even right now, like, the amount of
times I say, okay, walk me through and teach me what you just did.
And it
will take, I will spend a ton of time going down that wormhole,
but I think it's still valuable. and I think it helps me not short circuit the educational
experience.
I think for me I'm using AI mostly as like a way to get out of things that I don't really
want to spend a lot of time on. That makes sense, and I don't particularly see myself as
like using them down the road.
Yeah, I think that's useful. I've definitely had semesters where I feel I'd maybe too much
on AI, and that wasn't helpful for me, for my... learning, so I'm definitely a
little more like, use it as little as possible, but like for things it can easily automate,
that's so, so beneficial. I just, I think we're on two opposite episodes of the spectrum
right now where you're relying on it like a lot right now, and I'm like, I don't want to
touch this
stuff, but. Yeah,
and it's been hard, because my internship, honestly, I thought it would be, like, showing
me that, like, I need to not use AI as much, and then, like, I got here and I don't know
if you're familiar with, like, Gemini notebooks and, like, Gemma, and, like, all of those
new features.
I spent, I spent probably a quarter to a half of my day, every day, using those tools
and either trying to break them, trying to make them work quicker, or trying to find ways
to, like, share them on, like, a larger scale. Like, that's all I'm doing. And then, like,
of course, going through as they work to, like, make sure they did the math right and they
have the equations, right?
You know what I mean, that, like, their reasoning isn't flawed, but I don't think I've had,
I can, I mean, I've been here since May. I can count on one hand. I think the times the AI
has gotten, like, the equation wrong for something, like, engineering related in
the sense that, like, it performed a calculation that was just false, or it was just wrong.
You know what I mean? Like, maybe four times. Yeah.
and so
just me knowing how to do it those four times was incredibly helpful but I think what it
really has done is like really lowered the barrier to entry of like going in and deep diving
into like specific things
I don't know
okay yeah no I can see that as
far as like the culture though like I think there has to be a balance like we have to use
it we can't say hey we're not going to touch that that being said I'm probably overusing
it for the extent where like probably
underusing it. So we just
need to...
You've got to find the balance where you use it, but you understand how you're using it and
what it's doing. We're like, I'm, yeah, I'm definitely in this sense where, like, sometimes
I don't understand everything of why it's happening. It just kind of does, and I just kind
of accept that, like, it has done its job well and move on, especially for, like, coding
things. When I plus run, and it runs, and it works like it's supposed to, I don't ask a ton
of questions. and just if I, and once I kind of like understand it a little bit, because
I just don't,
it's interesting, very interesting. When it comes back to, like, school, like, I feel like
how I always use the AI is, like a better way where, like, I use it a lot to, like, study
for things, but not necessarily to solve the exact problems I was solving, but maybe to solve
other problems. It makes any sense, like, just create additional problems. So you can see
the
workflow so that you can go do your own.
Yeah, but it was also very interesting in my thermodynamics class, the teacher really encouraged
AI research, although he's no longer teaching here.
Who was the teacher?
I forgot. He was an older,
bald man.
Okay, so it wasn't Magelby then, right?
No, thermodynamics was it wasn't Magelby, and it wasn't Dylan. It was someone else.
I'd recommend taking it from Dr. Dylan.
I already took it, but thank you.
Who did you take it with?
I took it with Dylan.
Did you? Okay, yeah.
I didn't like mine in the class, but it was a very interesting perspective on using AI to
learn.
Yeah, where are you actually at in the program right now? Because I'm starting capstone,
but it seems like I just took thermos, so.
I've got two more years still. Okay. I'm trying to do the program in four years, and so
I've got two more.
Like, this is the semester I'm taking like manufacturing and mechatronet. things
like
that. Manufacturing is awesome. Mechatronics,
it can be awesome. You're not allowed to use AIMA to watch out.
yeah,
but it can be so rewarding when something works and when it doesn't work, it's like,
oh,
interesting class.
Manufacturing is so much fun, though.
What else were you in?
Oh, I don't know offhand, but, you don't know. the writing class.
Yeah, that one's just a work.
Is it fun or is it just kind of busy work? Well, like
parts of it are fun. I mean, assuming every class has the same kind of flow, like the first
project is like, you're going to write a set of instructions for someone and you need to
make it really pretty easy to follow and stuff like that. And that's actually fun. And then
you have like your assortment of papers that you have to do that are less fun. But you get
you get to do. them done and it's right
though yeah I feel like that's a good use of AI to like use it to write instructions like
give it a bunch of data and processes and then have it write the instructions and then just
verify that it was good
I don't know okay
maybe not I mean
you also have to everything you submit you have to say what you used AI for and stuff like
that so just make sure whatever you use it for you're comfortable declaring to the professor